Helder Quental

Self-motivated and driven Senior studying Information Technology concentrated in Cybersecurity at the New Jersey Institute of Technology. Through my previous leadership experiences, I was able to gain the knowledge and develop an understanding of team development, specifically the leadership aspect of it. My previous experiences from my studies gave me first-hand experience working with many kinds of applications and has given me the knowledge that I am prepared to apply in a professional workplace environment.



Ha33@njit.edu





linkedin.com/in/helderquental2020



Newark, NJ

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology Specialization in Cybersecurity

New Jersey Institute of Technology Major GPA 3.13 Newark, NJ Expected Graduation: December 2020

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE -

Forklift Operator/ Parts Worker

Campbell Supply Co.

May 2018 - September 2018

Newark, NJ

- Worked with a team of part workers to locate label and sell parts for automobiles.
- Primary focus to oversee forklift safety protocols for OSHA.
- Provided customer service through order fulfillments, service, and invoices.

Shift Leader/ Team Member

Quick Chek

June 2016 – August 2016

Harrison, NJ

- Supervised staff and completed daily assignments.
- Managed accounts and store orders.
- Responsible for customer service requests.

Kitchen Manager/ Crew Member

Chipotle Mexican Grill

September 2015 - December 2017

Clifton, NJ

- Supervised staff and completing daily assignments.
- Managed inventory and placing orders to re-stock.
- Organized daily accounts along with store opening and closing tasks.

LEADERSHIP EXPERIENCE —



\$ 82nd John O'Mosley Leadership School

Leadership School

July 2017

Phoenix, AZ

- Attended numerous lectures and seminars of developing social and professional skills
- Volunteered over 15 hours for the event

LANGUAGES •

- English Full professional proficiency
- Portuguese (Brazilian Dialect) Full professional proficiency
- Spanish Limited professional proficiency

Affiliations •

NJIT Association of Computing

Sept. 2018 - Present

Member

NJIT Deans List

January 2018 - Present

Member

Technical Skills

- Programming Languages: Java, Python, HTML, JavaScript, SQL, Bash, PHP
- Operating Systems: Windows 10, 8, MAC OS, Linux, Android, IOS
- Applications: Microsoft Office, PHPmyAdmin, RabbitMQ, Adobe Illustrator, Unity, WordPress, Eclipse
- Network Management: Ability to design and create SoHo (Small Office Home Office) networks
- Network Security: Ability to configure networks using software and hardware to implement and enhance data security (Basics of Cyber Security)

Relevant Coursework

- Advanced Data Structures in Java
- Computer Systems and Networks
- Database Design and Mamt
- Designing and Implementing Wireless Networks
- Ethical Hacking
- Computer and Network Security
- Internet Application and Databases
- Introduction to System
 Administration of Linux Systems

Projects

• Weather Application: HTML,

JavaScript, PHP

- Created a weather application within the schools AFS Network, using an API to gather the necessary information.
- Rock, Paper, Scissors: Python, MATLAB
- Created a simple form of the random game of rock, paper, scissors. Created in two different variations.